Lady Keigetsu. I'm here to pick you up.
SHU CLAN COURT LADY - LEELEE
A plain washed-scarlet garment...
SHU CLAN MAIDEN - SHU KEIGETSU
(SOUL OF REIRIN)
She must serve the Shu clan.
I wonder if she is a lower court lady?
The Noble Consort has given orders
for me to assist you in your relocation.
Relocation?
She said someone
who created a ruckus in the inner court
cannot be treated the same as before,
even if innocent.
I understand.
Please lead the way.
Um, you are....
I am Leelee.
Leelee.
I have been serving at your side
for the past year.
But I suppose this is
your level of recognition of me.
Huh?
She is a personal court lady?
You could have some doubt about
whether or not I am the actual person.
THOUGH I AM
AN INEPT VILLAINESS
INNER COURT
PALACE OF THE VERMILLION STALLION
(SHU PALACE)
So this is the Shu Palace.
Of the five clans
representing the Kingdom of Ei,
the Shu clan governed
the southern lands and revered fire.
IMPERIAL CAPITAL
THE WEST
KINGDOM OF EI
SHU CLAN
SOUTHERN LANDS
So gorgeous, with powerful coloring.
KOU CLAN
CENTRAL LANDS
RAN CLAN
EASTERN LANDS
KIN CLAN
WESTERN LANDS
GEN CLAN
NORTHERN LANDS
Oh?
Leelee.
Um, I'd like to say hello
to Noble Consort Shu.
I have been told by the Noble Consort
that you need to restrain yourself.
That can't be.
In the inner court,
the Consort and the Maiden
are supposed to have a bond
similar to mother and child.
EMPRESS - KOU KENSHUU
If this was my aunt,
she would try to hear me out first.
Although, if I really
had committed a crime,
she would cut off my head
by her own hand.
Perhaps Noble Consort Shu
is quite cold-blooded?
However...
she is one to be affectionate
even to insects.
NOBLE CONSORT
SHU GABI
I cannot possibly think
she has a cold heart.
My, how smelly.
There are two rats scurrying about,
a black rat and a red rat.
The middle court ladies
saying that to a Maiden.
In Kou Palace, everyone gave me
kind words as I walked down the street.
CONGRATULATIONS ON YOUR RECOVERY
-Lady Reirin!
-Your fever has gone down!
Please make sure to eat up!
Oh? It happened all the time,
so I didn't make a fuss.
Perhaps that was a bit abnormal?
I would like to be more independent.
My dream is a self-sufficient life!
This is your new room.
Oh.
This is...
This used to be a pantry.
Now that it has been abandoned,
it is fertile ground
for insects and fungi.
Across the street
is the Ran clan's estate.
Which means this is the farthest reaches
of the Shu Palace.
I have been exiled.
I will be living here?
Yeah, that's right.
Leelee?
I'm sure you tried to kill her, right?
You got cast off in a place like this
because you're the biggest idiot!
Taking care of you
in an abandoned building?
They're basically telling me
to die with you!
Why are you so surprised?
You've mocked me for all this time,
calling me a vulgar dancer's girl!
No matter how much you smooth it over,
the blood of your seductive mother
won't go away.
Cowering now that I've shown
my true nature? That's absurd!
Amber eyes.
Hair with a strong shade of red.
A speech pattern
similar to residents of the outer city.
I assume someone in the Shu clan had
a relationship with an immigrant dancer.
And that's why she is given the
lowest-ranking washed-scarlet garments,
even though she is a personal court lady.
I won't be holding back anymore!
I still have my court lady's room left.
I won't be sleeping here,
so you can clean this place up
and do laundry all by yourself!
Huh? By myself?
I'm sure none of the court ladies
you have abused will help you out, either!
Noble Consort Shu
said you won't take part
in the Ghost Festival
in seven days, either.
Make yourself at home.
Will I be living here?
In such a...
wonderful place?
Grass as far as I can see!
Fertile soil.
And...
freedom!
I can grow as many medicinal herbs,
experiment, sleep,
and be as rowdy as I want to!
From a young age, I always had a frail
body and kept making everyone worry.
Reirin, put some grit
into anything you do.
The Kou clan are servants of the earth.
My aunt mentioned that we take pride
in standing on our own two feet
and even appreciated our hardships.
All right!
I will do my best with grit!
Captain.
EUNUCH - BUNKOU
Though she was innocent
in the Lion's Judgment,
is there really a need for us
to go check on Shu Keigetsu?
CAPTAIN OF THE EAGLE EYES - SHIN-U
It's because His Highness is worried.
Make sure Reirin is not harmed again.
CROWN PRINCE - EI GYOUMEI
Stay on guard.
So that's what this is about.
His Highness is so devoted to Lady Reirin.
Oh.
But still, the Shu clan exiled
their Maiden to a place like this?
Hmph. Serves her right.
Eunuchs cannot harm a Maiden at all.
She took advantage of that rule.
Everyone was tormented so much
because of that.
And now she is facing torment.
I'm sure she's in her old room
throwing a tantrum
that she doesn't want to leave there?
I'd be willing to bet--
-Oh?
-Huh?
Oh, my. Captain of the Eagle Eyes
and Master Bunkou.
I hope you are having a good day.
Shu Keigetsu?
Oh? No--
I mean, yes. That's right.
What exactly are you doing here?
As you can see, weeding the area.
I was thinking I would prepare this area
to live comfortably.
What happened to your personal court lady?
Um, uh--
Right. She is out on an errand.
She's been abandoned.
Oh?
It would be wonderful
if I could prepare some tea for you two,
but unfortunately
this is the situation I am in.
Tea? I can understand for the Captain,
but for an eunuch?
It pains my heart to keep you two here,
as you are both busy.
So if you'll excuse me...
Is there something you would like to have?
Something to have?
Oh, no, if I were to be assisted
by everyone, including you, Captain,
the actual charm of this would be lost.
-Charm?
-Oh, nothing.
However, if I am able
to take advantage of your kindness...
Here it comes.
All this meekness is just an act!
-She's gonna ask for a whole lot.
-No, but, hmm...
A court lady, money,
or word with Noble Consort Shu.
Would you get me some salt?
-Salt?
-That's all?
I am quite fortunate here,
and it seems I will be able to procure
rainwater and potatoes.
However, I don't think
I will be able to make some salt in a day.
Is that really Shu Keigetsu?
After the Lion's Judgment,
she did say she was a different person
from her previous self.
I assume she fully repented
in the dungeon.
I see. The power of the underground
dungeon sure is something.
Now, Bunkou, you have lost your bet...
Wha?
CULINARY UNIT
I beg of you, culinary matron.
May I somehow get enough food for
the two of us, myself and Lady Keigetsu?
I told you. I have no food
to give to the disgraceful Shu Maiden
and a dancer's girl.
You're in the way. Stand aside.
Damn it.
I mouthed off to Shu Keigetsu
that I won't take care of her.
But if I can't get any food,
I'm also going to die of starvation.
If I can't expect to get any help
from the Shu Palace,
I have to go beg at another palace.
-You there.
-Hmm?
Ivory silk.
Why is an upper court lady
from the Kin clan approaching me?
What can I do for you, lady of ivory silk?
The sun will set soon,
so I will cut right to the chase.
My poor washed-scarlet girl.
Would you like to be a court lady
for the Kin clan?
What?
I have heard of the punishment
for Shu Keigetsu.
You got pulled into it, did you not?
Even if you were the daughter of a dancer,
you were not born wishing to be so.
How pitiful.
It pains the heart of my Maiden,
the wise Lady Kin Seika.
Lady Kin Seika?
KIN CLAN MAIDEN
KIN SEIKA
Therefore, given certain conditions,
I shall grant you
a garment of silver ermine.
Silver ermine? That is the color of
the middle court ladies of the Kin clan!
Wh-What would those conditions be?
It is quite simple.
I would like you to torture
the one you serve, Shu Keigetsu.
What?
Why would another clan retaliate
for what happened to Lady Reirin?
Listen.
Lady Reirin is
His Highness's favored butterfly.
If you seek favor from His Highness,
simply volunteer yourself
and swear devotion to Lady Reirin.
In other words, keep Shu Keigetsu down,
and play it out as if the Kin clan
is on Kou Reirin's side.
The Kin clan
is the heart of Ei's economy.
Kin Seika, with her merchant's spirit,
seeks to intentionally go for the seat
of secondary Maiden.
But excessive punishment will be
frowned upon by the Eagle Eyes Captain.
Such words from you, who approved
of banishment to an abandoned building.
I am Gayou of the Kin clan.
Starting tomorrow, I will give you
a reward for providing me a report
at this time of day
on how Shu Keigetsu is doing.
Or would you prefer this?
Rice?
I will have double this tomorrow.
You will accept, yes?
This isn't necessarily a bad thing.
It's so that I can survive.
Yes.
Surely by now, Shu Keigetsu
will be surrounded by grass and insects,
broken down in tears.
I recall being banished
to the garden one winter
after she said I had
an evil look in my eyes.
If she rubs her face to the ground
and begs for forgiveness,
I'll give her one bite.
I'll make her pay
for everything she's done to me until now.
Oh, welcome back.
Leelee, you came back!
I just finished frying the potatoes.
I also sautéed some field mustard.
Now let's eat while it's hot!
-Huh?
-And please take a look!
I am halfway done
with preparation of the fields.
A vast variety of plants were mixed up,
so I sorted them by type.
Potatoes, chives, gourds, and--
Hold on a second!
Why are potatoes and gourds
coming out of an abandoned building?
Did you use some forbidden magic
or something?
Oh, Leelee.
I cannot use any forbidden magic.
It was just wonderfully good luck
piling up.
This used to be a pantry, right?
The abandoned foodstuff
had secretly germinated here.
What?
After all, we are on the border of
the Ran clan, who are servants of wood.
Perhaps this area is filled
with qi that nurtures plants.
This really is like paradise.
No way. I mean, the rumors say this place
is where horrible fungi
and insects come from.
Fungi! Right, fungi!
The black smut spores
really did a wonderful job!
Take a look.
The wild rice
has turned into wonderful rice galls!
I am so thankful for them!
Oh, I am blessed with an opportunity
to put all of the knowledge I have
built up through books into action.
I am such a fortunate person!
Oh, bottomless stamina...
Potatoes!
Let's hurry up and eat!
It has always been a dream of mine
to eat food with an abundance of oil
sprinkled with salt,
and not have to worry about heartburn!
Wait, how did you get a hold
of salt and oil?
Oh, I received them from the kindness
of the Eagle Eyes Captain, among others.
Seriously?
Yes. As for salt, I was thinking
I could just use my tears
as a condiment if need be.
But I really wanted
to sprinkle it on lavishly,
so it was the right choice to indulge!
Wait, where did you come up
with such a train of thought?
What's gotten into her?
She's like a completely different person.
You really are Shu Keigetsu, right?
If you've got something
up your sleeve, spill it right now.
As of the night
of the Double Sevens Festival,
I have become
a completely different person.
It seems that is all I can say
from my own mouth at present time.
Now, Leelee...
say, "Ahh."
I am overjoyed!
Such happiness.
Even if I keep smelling oil,
I don't feel faint!
-I could eat forever!
-She's powerful.
-Can I...
-And I can drink!
Will I be able
to push this girl to despair?
KOU CLAN MAIDEN - KOU REIRIN
(SOUL OF KEIGETSU)
Lady Reirin,
is there something you need right now?
No, please don't worry about me.
Lady Reirin, your perseverance
is a wonderful virtue.
But if you choose not to rely on us,
it makes us feel rather dejected.
Please let us know of even the most
marginal of changes without hesitation.
Oh, all of you worry so much.
I'm fine. Please stand down.
How nice it feels
to be spoiled and worried about.
This is exactly what I had been seeking.
When one is cherished this much,
even a sewer rat will become
an elegant, delicate butterfly.
It was an impossibility to begin with.
A girl from the countryside
that can do a bit of forbidden magic
trying to curry the favor
of His Highness in the Maiden Court.
My father was a fallen sorcerer
and my mother was of the lowest rank
among the Shu clan.
One year ago, their debts piled up,
and they committed suicide.
So I became a maid for the main Shu clan.
You lost your parents
at such an early age.
That is so pitiful.
Noble Consort Shu, who had been
visiting her family home by coincidence,
took to me at first sight
and assigned me to be her Maiden.
But I had no aptitude.
I was chosen only out of pity.
That was where I ran out of luck.
The court ladies mocked me,
and the Noble Consort could only fret.
The other Maidens in the Maiden Court
simply ridiculed me.
But that girl was different.
She was beautiful, intelligent,
and had the perfect personality.
That's why I hated her.
It makes me want to vomit.
Lady Reirin.
His Highness is here to see you.
Kou Reirin. This is all your fault.
I will take His Highness from you.
Reirin, I apologize for making you
feel uneasy during the Lion's Judgment.
I am all right.
It simply pains my heart
that I make you worry, dear cousin.
It's unusual for you
to fawn on me like this.
Oh, how good this feels.
Now that I think about it,
I'm glad that girl didn't die.
In the unlikely possibility
that the switch is exposed,
I can just take her hostage.
After all, I'm the only one that can
return us to our original bodies.
In any case, this body is way too frail.
Pardon me, Lady Reirin.
REIRIN'S HEAD COURT LADY
KOU TOUSETSU
Is something the matter, Tousetsu?
Yes. It has been two days
since your fever has started.
So I brought you your training items.
Huh?
Embroidering all night,
handwriting 100 sutras,
dance lessons,
musical instrument lessons...
or training basic stamina.
What will it be tonight?
What is she talking about?
She's talking to a sick person!
"When my life is in peril is when my body
most greedily gains knowledge and skill."
"When my head is hazy with a fever
is when I can see beyond my limits."
Lady Reirin, you casually said so
the first time I was nursing you.
Each time I remember it,
I feel shivers all over my body!
And Lady Reirin,
you inherited the Kou blood
that reveres effort
more than anyone else.
I, Tousetsu, am personally proud
that I can accompany you on your training,
especially now that the Empress
joins in on the action.
Now, as you please.
T-Tousetsu? You know...
I have a fever that makes it painful
for me to even sit up.
Then you are in perfect condition.
I-I feel nauseous.
I think the fever is getting even worse.
It looks like you will reach
heights never seen before, then!
-What?
-I will bring a washtub.
Oh, no!
This is....
an illness that may spread, I believe.
Please step back.
Right now.
I would not be able to forgive myself
if something were ever
to happen to you dear people.
Lady Reirin.
Oh, my, to think your physical condition
was this terrible.
I will call for the apothecary right away!
Please hold yourself steady!
We are right here with you!
These guys are insane.
Definitely insane.
Wasn't Kou Reirin a delicate butterfly
protected and spoiled by everyone?
Can it be that everyone is overprotective
because she physically overexerts herself
to the brink of death,
forcing them all to be really worried?
I can...
keep going in this body, right?
Oh.
What are you doing here?
There isn't a place
for rats to sleep here anymore.
I'm so frustrated.
I shall grant you
a garment of silver ermine.
I would like you to torture
the one you serve, Shu Keigetsu.
I'll do anything
if it means I can get out of this place!